In this beginner assignment we're going to make a
この初級のレッスンでは とてもシンプルですが
very simple but playable 2D game
十分楽しめる2D ゲームを作成します
to use many of the basic concepts
初心者チュートリアルモジュールから
from the beginner tutorial modules.
たくさんの基礎的なコンセプトを使ってみましょう。
We'll be making a 2D UFO game
これから、2D の UFO ゲームを作って
where we'll be collecting gold nuggets.
金塊を集めてみましょう。
We'll see how to create new game objects,
ゲームを作るために 以下のことを学びます
add components to these game objects,
新しいゲームオブジェクトの作り方
set the values on their properties,
ゲームオブジェクトにコンポーネントを加える方法
and position these game objects in the scene
プロパティーに値を設定する方法
to create a game.
シーンにゲームオブジェクトを配置する方法 です。
In our game the player will control
プレイヤーは上下動する 2D ビューで
a UFO flying around the game board in a
ゲームボードを飛び回る
top-down 2D view.
UFO を制御します
We'll move the UFO using physics and forces.
UFO　は物理と力学を使って動かします
We'll look at the input from the player
プレイヤーがキーボードから入力し
through the keyboard and we'll use those inputs
その入力に基づいて
to apply forces to the UFO,
UFO へ力を適用し
making it move in our scene.
シーンで動かします
We'll see how to detect contact between
UFO と取得するゲームオブジェクトの接触を
the UFO and the pickup game objects
検知する方法と
and use these events to collect
そのイベントを利用して
the pickup game objects.
アイテムのゲームオブジェクトを集める方法を学びます
When we've done we'll have made a simple
このチュートリアルが終わるころには
UFO game where the player controls the
シンプルな UFO ゲームが出来上がります。
UFO with the keyboard, picks up and counts
そのゲームでは キーボードで UFO を制御し
special collectable objects,
特別なアイテムのオブジェクトを取得して数え
displays the current count,
その時点の総数を示し
and ends the game when all of the
そのゲームオブジェクトがすべて取得されると
game objects have been picked up.
ゲームが終了します
To complete this project we'll use custom
このプロジェクトを完成するために
created 2D art assets
カスタム製の2D アートアセットを使います
which can be downloaded from the
それらはUnity Asset Store から
Unity Asset Store.
ダウンロードできます
Let's begin by creating a new project.
それでは 新しいプロジェクトを作ってみましょう
First open the Unity editor
はじめに Unity エディターが開いていなければ
if you haven't done that already.
開いてください
You can create a new project by
新規のプロジェクトを作成するには
choosing File - New Project.
File > New Project の順に選択します
This will bring us to the home screen.
こうすると ホームスクリーンが表示されます
On the home screen you can create a
ホームスクリーンで 2 通りのやり方で
new project either by hitting the
新規プロジェクトを作成できます
blue Create New Project button
1 つめは 画面中央の
in the centre of the window,
青い New Project ボタンを押します
or by clicking the New button
もう 1 つのやり方は 画面上方の
at the top of the window.
New ボタンを押します
The first thing that we need to do is
まず
to give our project a name,
プロジェクトに名前をつけます
I'm going to call the project UFO Game.
このゲームを「UFO ゲーム」と呼ぶことにします
The next thing we need to do is set the
次にやることは 新しいプロジェクトの
destination, or path, to our new project.
保存場所を設定することです
I'm going to put this new project on my desktop.
このプロジェクトはデスクトップに置くことにします
You'll see we have a choice
ご覧のように
to set the project preferences
プロジェクトは3D か2D
to either 3D or 2D mode.
お好きなモードに設定できます
Since we're working in 2D
現在 2D で作業しているので
I'm going to click 2D.
2D をクリックします
This will set the preferences for the Unity editor
これで Unity エディターの環境設定と
to useful defaults for creating 2D game.s
2D ゲームの作成に役立つデフォルトが設定されます
For more information on working in 2D,
2D で作業するための詳細については
please see the information linked below.
下のリンクのページの情報を参照してください
Now click the Create Project button
それではCreate Project ボタンを押して
to create our new project.
新規プロジェクトを作成してみましょう
Unity will create a new empty scene
Unity が新しい空のシーンを作るので
for us to work in.
そこで作業をします
The first thing we'll need to do is to download
最初にUnity Asset Store から
and import our art assets
アートアセットをダウンロードして
from the Unity Asset Store.
インポートします
To access the Asset Store choose
Asset Store にアクセスするには
Window - Asset Store.
Window > Asset Store の順に選んでください
Or use the keyboard shortcut
または キーボードのショートカットも使えます
command + 9  on mac,
Mac では command + 9
or control + 9 on windows.
Windows では control + 9 です
The Asset Store is a service that
Asset Store は
Unity Technologies provides
Unity Technologies が提供するサービスです
where creators can both buy and sell
Asset Store では 製作者がゲーム制作のために
assets to make games.
アセットを売買できます
These include art, music, scripts, effects,
アート、音楽、スクリプト、エフェクトなど
all the way up to complete games and projects.
ゲームやプロジェクトを完成させるためのすべてが揃っています
Unity also publishes content
Asset Store にはUnity からパブリッシュされた
to the Asset Store, including teaching
コンテンツもあります
projects like this one to help
その中には このビデオのような
you learn how to make games.
ゲームの作り方を学べる学習プロジェクトなども含まれます。
By default the Asset Store is
デフォルトでは Asset Store は
opened as a docked tab.
ドッキングした状態で開きます
Let's undock the tab so that we can
切り離してフローティングの状態にすると
expand the window.
画面を引き延ばすことができます
In the upper-right corner of
引き延ばしたAsset Store ウィンドウの
the expanded Asset Store window
右上に
we'll see a listing of asset categories.
アセットカテゴリーのリストがあります
At the bottom we should find
その 1 番下に
Unity Essentials.
Unity Essentials があります
Expand this category and we'll find
このカテゴリを広げると
a subcategory called Sample Projects.
Sample Projects というサブカテゴリが表示されます
Within Sample Projects we'll find
Sample Projects の中に
an item called 2D UFO tutorial.
「2D UFO チュートリアル」というアイテムがあります
Click on the item title to open it.
そのタイトルをクリックして開いてください
Once the page loads we'll see a
ページがロードされると
download button in the upper-left corner.
左上の角にDownloadボタンがあります
Click on the Download button to begin
Download ボタンをクリックすると
downloading the assets.
そのアセットをダウンロードし始めます
The Download button will be replaced
いったん Download ボタンを押すと
by the percentage of the download completed
ボタンは ダウンロードが終了したパーセンテージの
once we click on it.
表示に代わります
Once the download is complete we'll see
ダウンロードが終わると
a dialogue labelled Importing Complete Project.
Importing Complete Project というダイアログが現れます
This warns us that importing a
このダイアログは プロジェクトすべてをインポートすると
complete project will overwrite
現在のプロジェクト設定が上書きされることを
our current project settings.
警告しています
In this case, because we've just created a
今回は新しいプロジェクトを作成したばかりなので
new project this is fine.
問題ありません
Click the Import button to continue.
Import ボタンを押して続けましょう
Next we'll be given a choice
次に
of which assets we would like to
プロジェクトにインポートしたいアセットを
import in to our project.
選択できます
The default is All, which is what we want,
デフォルトではすべて選択になっています
so go ahead and click Import.
丁度そうしようと思っていたので　そのまま　Import　をクリックします
Close the Asset Store window.
Asset Store ウィンドウを閉じます
We now have our new project with our assets imported.
これで新しいプロジェクトに必要なアセットをインポートし終わりました
And the default new empty scene open.
デフォルトの新しい空のシーンが開いている状態です
Before creating anything in the new scene
新しいシーンで何かを作成する前に
we need to save our scene.
シーンを保存する必要があります
We can save our scene by choosing
シーンを保存するには
File - Save Scene,
File > Save Scene の順に選択します
or by using the keyboard shortcut
または、キーボードショートカットを使用します
command + S on mac,
Mac では command + S
or control + S on windows.
Windows では control + S です
I'm going to save this scene
このシーンを保存してみます
in the Assets directory in the
Assets ディレクトリの中の
folder called Scenes.
Scenes というフォルダーの中に保存します
I'm going to call the scene Main.
このシーンを Main と呼ぶことにします
We can now see in our Scenes folder
今では、Scenes フォルダーの中に
the scene called Main.
Main というシーンがあります
It's worth noting that the
ここで気づいてほしいのは
Completed, Prefabs, Scenes, Scripts
Completed, Prefabs, Scenes, Scripts, Sprites の
and Sprites folders
すべてのフォルダーが
were all created when we imported our asset package.
アセットパッケージをインポートしたときに作成されたことです
The Completed folder contains
Completed フォルダーには
a completed version of the project,
プロジェクトが完全な形で含まれているので
which you can refer to if you get stuck.
問題が起こった時に参照できます。
Great, that's the end of our first lesson.
これで、最初のレッスンは終わりです。
In our next lesson we're going to lay out our play field.
次のレッスンでは、プレイフィールドをレイアウトします。